# Sotetsu Koyamada

Graduate School of Informatics, Kyoto University Yoshidahonmachi 36-1, sakyo-ku, Kyoto-city, Kyoto, Japan. 606-8501 koyamada-s@sys.i.kyoto-u.ac.jp https://sotets.uk

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

My primary research interest is reinforcement learning, and I am particularly interested in both theoretical and practical interface between its algorithms and other fields of machine learning. I am also interested in neural networks, natural language processing, and sensitivity analysis in general as well.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Ph.D. candidate of Informatics

Apr 2015 - Present

Kyoto University Supervisor: Shin Ishii

#### **Master of Informatics**

Apr 2013 - Mar 2015

Kyoto University Supervisor: Shin Ishii

Thesis title: "Principal Sensitivity Analysis and Its Application to Knowledge Discovery in Functional Neuroimaging"

#### **Bachelor of Economics**

Apr 2008 - Mar 2013

Kyoto University

Supervisor: Masaaki Iiyama

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Research internship

Aug 2016 - Present

National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology, Japan Developed a new training objective function for neural sequence predict

Developed a new training objective function for neural sequence prediction, which generalizes the maximum likelihood-based and reinforcement learning-based objective functions using  $\alpha$ -divergence.

# Machine learning engineer

 $\mbox{Apr}\ 2015$  - Present

Recruit Holdings Co., Ltd., Japan

Constructed predictive APIs on Hadoop and Spark platform to improve KPI (key performance indicator) performances for more than 30 web services.

# Research internship

Oct 2013 - Mar 2015

ATR Cognitive Mechanisms Laboratories, Japan

Developed a subject-independent brain decoder using neural networks and proposed a new algorithm for data-driven scientific discovery from nonlinear classifiers.

#### RESEARCH Books

- S. Koyamada et al.: Japanese translation of "Algorithms for Reinforcement Learning" by C. Szepesvári, Kyoritsu Shuppan.
  - Chief editor. Managed the entire project ran by 12 team members.
  - Wrote an additional chapter about deep reinforcement learning.

#### Publications (refereed)

- S. Koyamada, Y. Kikuchi, A. Kanemura, S. Maeda, and S. Ishii: "Neural sequence model training via  $\alpha$ -divergence minimization." ICML Workshop on Learning to Generate Natural Language, 2017.
- S. Koyamada, M. Koyama, K. Nakae, and S. Ishii: "Principal sensitivity analysis." In Proceedings of the Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 621-632, 2015.
- S. Koyamada, Y. Shikauchi, K. Nakae, and S. Ishii: "Construction of subject independent brain decoders for human fMRI with deep learning." The International Conference on Data Mining, Internet Computing, and Big Data, 60-68, 2014.

### Pre-prints (not refereed)

• S. Koyamada, Y. Shikauchi, K. Nakae, M. Koyama, S. Ishii "Deep learning of fMRI big data: a novel approach to subject-transfer decoding." arXiv:1502.00093, 2015.

#### Other presentations (not refereed)

- S. Koyamada: "Principal Sensitivity Analysis." Machine Learning Summer School 2015 Kyoto, Kyoto, Sep 1, 2015 (poster presentation)
- S. Koyamada, Y. Shikauchi, K. Nakae, M. Koyama, and S. Ishii: "Knowledge Discovery for Nonlinear Classifier in Functional Neuroimaging." 10th AEARU Workshop on Computer Science and Web Technology, Tsukuba, Feb 26, 2015 (poster presentation)
- S. Koyamada, Y. Shikauchi, K. Nakae, and S. Ishii: "Learning the subject-independent discriminative features from the large-scale fMRI database." Neuro2014, Yokohama, Sep 13, 2014 (poster presentation)

# GRANTS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

# Student Scholarship

Apr 2013 - Mar 2015

Japan Student Services Organization (JASSO), Japan Approx. 1,056,000 yen

#### **TEACHING**

#### Teaching assistant

Jul 23, 2014

Lecture sessions on deep learning, Kyoto University, Japan

#### Teaching assistant

Oct 2013 - Mar 2014

"Introduction to Computer Science." Kyoto University, Japan

#### SKILLS Programming skills

- Programming language: Python, Go, C++, Java, R
  - GitHub repo: https://github.com/sotetsuk
- Deep learning framework: PyTorch, Chainer, TensorFlow
- Middleware/Infrastructure: Hadoop, Spark, RDBMS, AWS, GCP, Docker
- Other tools: Git, SQL, LaTeX

#### Language

Japanese (native), English